<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vertica on Maloy Manna</title>
    <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/tags/vertica/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vertica on Maloy Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2007 - 2025. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 09:59:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://maloymanna.github.io/tags/vertica/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thrive or Survive - the changing rules for databases</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/05/07/thrive-or-survive-the-changing-rules-for-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 09:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/05/07/thrive-or-survive-the-changing-rules-for-databases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not since the late seventies, when Larry Ellison&amp;rsquo;s Relational Software Inc. (RSI) turned out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/timeline/index.html&#34;&gt;first commerically available RDBMS&lt;/a&gt; - Oracle, has there been such rapid changing of the rules (read disruption) in the database industry.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;With &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web 2.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; pushing enterprise adoption, and the ensuing &lt;em&gt;information explosion&lt;/em&gt; in the maze of audio, video, data and ever-growing data warehouses, it seems that the conventional relational database systems are growing tired. With estimates of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;unstructured data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; being anywhere between 80% to 95% of all business data, and the ever changing requirements imposed by Web 2.0 - storage of &lt;em&gt;pictures&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;audio&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;video&lt;/em&gt;, the demands being made on conventional RDBMS technology are monstrous. With the load window available being fixed due to availability and uptime requirements, the ever increasing data to be loaded into data warehouses, the bulking-up of the data due to usage of &lt;em&gt;XML&lt;/em&gt; based formats, conflicting requirements of &lt;em&gt;SQL&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;XQuery&lt;/em&gt;, the database is also being challenged by the demands of business intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
