<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data scientist on Maloy Manna</title>
    <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/tags/data-scientist/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data scientist on Maloy Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2007 - 2020. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 22:52:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://maloymanna.github.io/tags/data-scientist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What roles do you need in your data science team?</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/06/24/what-roles-do-you-need-in-your-data-science-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 22:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/06/24/what-roles-do-you-need-in-your-data-science-team/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few weeks, we&amp;rsquo;ve had several conversations in our data lab regarding data engineering problems and day to day problems we face with unsupervised data scientists who find it difficult to deploy their code into production.
The opinions from business seemed to cluster around a tacit definition of data scientists as researchers, primarily from statistics or mathematics backgrounds, who are experienced in machine learning algorithms and often in some domain areas specific to our business, (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Big Data - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2013/08/21/basics-of-big-data-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 23:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2013/08/21/basics-of-big-data-part-1/</guid>
      <description>You can’t miss all the buzz about Big Data! Over the past few years, the buzz around the cloud and Big Data shaping most of the future of computing, IT and analytics in particular has grown incessantly strong. As with most buzz words, which are then hijacked by marketing to suit their own products’ storylines, but which nonetheless manage to confuse users in business and staff in IT as well, Big Data means several things to several people.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>