<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data mining on Maloy Manna</title>
    <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/tags/data-mining/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data mining on Maloy Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2007 - 2020. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 12:55:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://maloymanna.github.io/tags/data-mining/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Big Data - Building a Hadoop data warehouse</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/05/12/basics-of-big-data-building-a-hadoop-data-warehouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 12:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/05/12/basics-of-big-data-building-a-hadoop-data-warehouse/</guid>
      <description>This is the 3rd part of a series of posts on Big Data. Read Part-1 (What is Big Data) and Part-2 (Hadoop).
Traditionally data warehouses have been built with relational databases as backbone. With the new challenges (3Vs) of Big Data, relational databases have been falling short of the requirements of handling
 New data types (unstructured data) Extended analytic processing Throughput (TB/hour loading) with immediate query access  The industry has turned to Hadoop as a disruptive solution for these very challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trends in Business Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/12/10/trends-in-business-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2007 20:33:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/12/10/trends-in-business-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>By definition Business Intelligence (BI) has been about making decisions based on information obtained from meaningful data. At one point of time we had terms like decision support systems (DSS) to define technology which has finally evolved into BI as we know it now. Or has it? Somewhere along the line, we became entangled in the technology aspect of it and with all the buzzwords of data warehousing, data mining, dimensional modeling, data marts, **CRM **and **SCM **it is not difficult to see why.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>