<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Maloy Manna</title>
    <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Maloy Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2007 - 2025. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://maloymanna.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI is all you need</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2025/01/19/ai-is-all-you-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2025/01/19/ai-is-all-you-need/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/images/genai-banner2.png&#34; alt=&#34;The AI present and future&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/images/genai-banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;Images generated by AI&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no escaping the buzz around &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt;(artificial intelligence) these days. And yet, it&amp;rsquo;s hardly a couple of years before the pandemic, that Big Tech was relying heavily on human-input to fine-tune their models, something that used to be called the &lt;em&gt;last mile problem of AI&lt;/em&gt;. e.g. Amazon was using its infamous &lt;em&gt;Mechanical Turk&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/not-always-ai-that-sifts-through-sensitive-info-crowdsourced-labor/&#34;&gt;crowdsource cheap human labor for tasks like verifying AI inputs or labeling data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Data Mesh Approach</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2024/06/28/the-data-mesh-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2024/06/28/the-data-mesh-approach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With rapid advance in the technology world, it makes sense sometimes to rethink our objective and outline the roadmap instead of just following the new and shiny. &lt;span style=&#34;color: blue;&#34;&gt;Data Mesh&lt;/span&gt; might seem a relatively new concept, however what its creator Zhamak Dehghani has done is spell out in words the approach required to reach the strategic goal of being a data-driven organization.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/post/data-mesh.png&#34; alt=&#34;Data Mesh domain product notation&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Figure: Data Mesh domain product notation, adapted from Zhamak Dehghani&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delta Lake and the Lakehouse Architecture</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2024/05/19/delta-lake-and-the-lakehouse-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2024/05/19/delta-lake-and-the-lakehouse-architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The technology world often sees upheavals when disparate concepts are put together to achieve different objectives, creating something which is much &lt;em&gt;more than the sum of its parts&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;span style=&#34;color: blue;&#34;&gt;Delta Lake&lt;/span&gt; is one such concept, which has melded log and ACID, bringing transaction and atomicity concepts into the ETL-analytics-big.data field, creating a revolution of sorts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem(s):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Since traditional data warehousing, the design and modeling of analytics systems relied on &lt;strong&gt;denormalized&lt;/strong&gt; tables, as analytics systems were considered separate from transactional systems. This started to change with the move to the cloud and availability of more real-time data. With the advent of big data technology like HDFS/Hadoop, additional constraints on updates and storage of relational datasets were added due to performance costs. The difficulty was particularly acute for cloud customers who faced additional latency compared to on-premises HDFS/Hadoop users.&#xA;GDPR compliance meant deleting or correcting customer data required massive table-wide updates for a few records, with increased probability of data corruption and consistency issues in case of crashed updates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identity Basics 2 - Permissions, Scopes and Consent</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2023/04/09/identity-basics-2-permissions-scopes-consent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 08:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2023/04/09/identity-basics-2-permissions-scopes-consent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my previous post, we saw how app registrations add identity configurations for applications on Azure AD. Just like a user, an application would also require access to resources like Microsoft Graph, which need authorization. The resource owner can grant(consent) or deny this authorization to the application.&#xA;There are mainly 2 &lt;em&gt;access scenarios&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delegated access&lt;/strong&gt; - access on behalf of a signed-in user.&#xA;User is signed-into a client application, which access the resource on behalf of the user. This requires &lt;em&gt;delegated permissions&lt;/em&gt; (also referred to as &lt;em&gt;scopes&lt;/em&gt;). All scenarios involving user actions should use delegated access. Also, scopes should be limited using the principle of least-privilege.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/graph/permissions-reference&#34;&gt;See also: the full list of Microsoft Graph permissions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;App-only access&lt;/strong&gt; - access without a user, as the application&amp;rsquo;s own identity. This scenario is when the application runs as a background service or daemon used for automation or backup, or the data can&amp;rsquo;t be scoped to a single user. The client app needs to be granted appropriate application roles of the resource app it&amp;rsquo;s calling to access the requested data. Application roles granted through consent are called &lt;em&gt;application permissions&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/post/access-scenarios.png&#34; alt=&#34;Access Scenarios&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identity Basics 1 - Application Registrations</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2023/03/18/identity-basics-1-app-registrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 17:04:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2023/03/18/identity-basics-1-app-registrations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For some time now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on security risk assessments of web applications. Modern identity management can be complex and often requires diving deep into the authentication flow and registration process to understand risk blocks in order to design appropriate controls and counter-measures. I hope to write a short series of posts to document the components and flows of this process, so that it can be my handy reference.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern authentication fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2022/11/12/modern-authentication-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 07:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2022/11/12/modern-authentication-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/2022/09/18/azure-iam-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Identity and Access Management (IAM)&lt;/a&gt;, I provided a very high-level view of how modern authentication works on the basis of a centralized Identity provider, like Azure Active Directory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, let&amp;rsquo;s look at a Microsoft Azure video, where Azure AD Program manager &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/stuartkwan/&#34;&gt;Stuart Kwan&lt;/a&gt; presents the basics of modern claims-based authentication in a lucid and eloquent way.&#xA;Clearly if a picture is worth a thousand words, a video is probably worth a million!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Security - Service endpoint vs Private endpoint</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2022/10/02/azure-security-service-endpoint-vs-private-endpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 11:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2022/10/02/azure-security-service-endpoint-vs-private-endpoint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: blue;&#34;&gt;Endpoints &lt;/span&gt; are a critical aspect of securing your resources in the cloud. When using Azure PaaS services, it is important to understand the differences between two types of endpoint available in Azure: service endpoint and private endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service endpoint:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;service endpoint&lt;/strong&gt; is a way of extending your virtual network’s private address space to Azure services over the Azure backbone network. When a service endpoint is enabled, traffic between your virtual network and the Azure service of your choice stays on the Azure backbone network, rather than going over the public internet. This provides better security and performance for your resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure IAM fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2022/09/18/azure-iam-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 07:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2022/09/18/azure-iam-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: blue;&#34;&gt;Identity and Access Management (IAM) &lt;/span&gt; is a framework of policies and technologies to ensure the right people or machines to access the right assets or resources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this digital age, an &lt;strong&gt;identity&lt;/strong&gt; can be either a human (user), a software component (application) or a hardware component (computer, mobile or IoT device). Just like any identity document in the real-world, identities serve is a way to authenticate and authorize access to assets and resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Control plane and Data plane</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2022/08/24/azure-control-plane-data-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 21:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2022/08/24/azure-control-plane-data-plane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Azure operations can be divided into 2 categories:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control plane (or Management plane)&lt;/strong&gt; - used to manage resources in azure subscriptions, e.g. creation of a virtual machine or a storage account&#xA;All requests for control plane operations are sent to the Azure Resource Manager URL. For Azure global, the url is: &lt;a href=&#34;https://management.azure.com&#34;&gt;https://management.azure.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data plane&lt;/strong&gt; - used to manage capabilties exposed by instances of resource types e.g. using remote desktop protocol (RDP) to interact with a virtual machine, or reading/writing data in a storage account.&#xA;Requests for data plane operations are sent to an endpoint specific to the instance of the resource type e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://myname.blob.core.windows.net&#34;&gt;https://myname.blob.core.windows.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power BI Security - Under the hood</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2018/07/08/power-bi-security-under-the-hood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 07:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2018/07/08/power-bi-security-under-the-hood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has been instrumental in pushing the envelope on managed self-service BI with it&amp;rsquo;s Power BI SaaS platform.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I wrote about this back in &lt;a href=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/11/13/review-of-the-bt-summit-cloud-computing-soa-and-bi-tracks/&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt; [1], when Microsoft was working on Project Gemini (later PowerPivot) used SQL Server Analysis Services as an in-memory engine, with data compression to really bring BI to the masses, so to speak.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Since then, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s vision of self-service BI evolved from providing Excel plug-ins viz. PowerPivot, Data Explorer (later renamed PowerQuery) and sharing bulky Excel files on SharePoint (with Power View [2]) to a manageable managed-self-service BI with the launch of Power BI in 2015.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Today, Power BI is powered by Azure, and deployed as a SaaS across datacenters in Microsoft regions across the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 features of modern data architectures</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2017/07/14/9-features-of-modern-data-architectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 11:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2017/07/14/9-features-of-modern-data-architectures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last few years has seen a massive change in the data landscape. With the rise of big data, there&amp;rsquo;s been rapid innovation in the tools, skills and roles working on data systems. Data architectures have evolved beyond monolithic, centralized databases and unwieldy analytic applications to distributed, scalable architectures with simpler collaborative and interactive analytic tools. In this post, I look at the defining features of modern data architectures.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern data architectures generally feature the following (though not all of these may be present in the same system):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kafka - building real-time stream data pipelines</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2017/05/01/kafka-building-real-time-stream-data-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 14:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2017/05/01/kafka-building-real-time-stream-data-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, Kafka has become the most exciting new addition in the big data distributed architecture. Originally developed at LinkedIn, its founders Jay Kreps, Jun Rao and Neha Narkhede have launched a company Confluent to develop its open-core business model. The software at its core, Apache Kafka reinvents the database log to provide a highly scalable and fault tolerant, high performance distributed system, which serves as the data pipeline backbone for stream data processing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hadoop&#39;s small files problem</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2016/02/16/hadoop-small-files-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 08:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2016/02/16/hadoop-small-files-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Small files are a big problem in Hadoop.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hadoop is designed to manage big data and by design this means HDFS is designed to store very large files in a distributed cluster with streaming access to this data. For reference, a typical block in HDFS is 64 MB or 128 MB. Each small file (few MB or less) is stored in a block and multiple small files could be stored in blocks across different nodes of the distributed cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data processing with Spark in R &amp; Python</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/11/18/data-processing-with-spark-in-r-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 11:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/11/18/data-processing-with-spark-in-r-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently gave a talk on data processing with Apache Spark using R and Python. tl;dr - the slides and presentation can be accessed below (free registration):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;slideshare-embed&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/5nBaQvLpL3zIHt&#34; &#xA;            width=&#34;595&#34; &#xA;            height=&#34;485&#34; &#xA;            frameborder=&#34;0&#34; &#xA;            marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; &#xA;            marginheight=&#34;0&#34; &#xA;            scrolling=&#34;no&#34; &#xA;            style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; &#xA;            allowfullscreen&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As noted in my previous &lt;a href=&#34;https://biguru.wordpress.com/2015/03/23/spark-big-data-platform-future/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, Spark has become the defacto standard for big data applications and has been adopted quickly by the industry. See Cloudera&amp;rsquo;s  &lt;a href=&#34;https://vision.cloudera.com/one-platform/&#34;&gt;One Platform&lt;/a&gt; initiative blog post by CEO Mike Olson for their commitment to Spark.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What roles do you need in your data science team?</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/06/24/what-roles-do-you-need-in-your-data-science-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 22:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/06/24/what-roles-do-you-need-in-your-data-science-team/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few weeks, we&amp;rsquo;ve had several conversations in our data lab regarding data engineering problems and day to day problems we face with unsupervised data scientists who find it difficult to deploy their code into production.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/post/datascience3.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Data scientist&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The opinions from business seemed to cluster around a tacit definition of data scientists as researchers, primarily from statistics or mathematics backgrounds, who are experienced in machine learning algorithms and often in some domain areas specific to our business, (e.g. actuaries in insurance), but not necessarily having skills of writing production-ready code.&#xA;The key driver behind the somewhat opposing strain of thought came from the developers and data engineers who often quoted Cloudera&amp;rsquo;s Director of Data Science - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/josh_wills&#34;&gt;Josh Wills&lt;/a&gt; - famous for his &amp;ldquo;definition of a data scientist tweet&amp;rdquo;:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Data Scientist (n.): Person who is better at statistics than any software engineer and better at software engineering than any statistician.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to Data Science</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/05/20/an-introduction-to-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 16:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/05/20/an-introduction-to-data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I presented a talk last week introducing Data Science and associated topics to some enthusiasts.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s a slide deck I created quickly with markdown using Swipe - a start-up building HTML5 presentation tools.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The contents include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Data scientist skills&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Data science: enablers and barriers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Big data analytics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Data science lifecycle&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use cases&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tools and technology&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Project approach&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Machine learning&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Skills and roles&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learning resources&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are the slides:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;figure class=&#34;swipe&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.swipe.to/embed/2675ch&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;style&gt;figure.swipe{display:block;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;height:0;overflow:hidden;}figure.swipe iframe{position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;border:none;}&lt;/style&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Spark is the big data platform of the future</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/03/23/spark-big-data-platform-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 12:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/03/23/spark-big-data-platform-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apache Spark&lt;/strong&gt; has created a lot of buzz recently. In fact, beyond the buzz, Apache Spark has seen phenomenal adoption and has been marked out as the successor to Hadoop MapReduce.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/post/apache-spark.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Apache Spark&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Google Trends confirms the &lt;strong&gt;hockey stick like growth&lt;/strong&gt; in interest in Apache Spark.  All leading Hadoop vendors, including Cloudera, now include Apache Spark in their Hadoop distribution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/post/googletrends.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;GoogleTrends - Apache Spark&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So what exactly is Spark, and why has it generated such enthusiasm? Apache Spark is an open-source big data processing framework designed for speed and ease of use.  Spark is well-known for its in-memory performance, but that has also given rise to misconceptions about its on-disk abilities. Spark is in fact a general execution engine - which has a greatly improved performance both in-memory as well as on-disk, when compared with older frameworks like MapReduce. With its advanced &lt;strong&gt;DAG&lt;/strong&gt; (directed acyclic graph) execution engine, Spark can run programs up to &lt;strong&gt;100x faster than MapReduce in memory, or 10x faster on-disk.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A gentle introduction to Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/02/04/a-gentle-introduction-to-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 23:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/02/04/a-gentle-introduction-to-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: blue;&#34;&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/span&gt; is a big part of big data and data science. A subset of artificial intelligence - a branch of science notorious for requiring advanced knowledge of mathematics. In practice though, most data scientists don&amp;rsquo;t try to build a &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/l6bmTNadhJE&#34;&gt;Chappie&lt;/a&gt;  and there are simpler, practical ways to get started with machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/post/selection_002.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Gmail Priority Inbox&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Machine learning in practice involves predictions based on data. Notable examples include Amazon&amp;rsquo;s product recommendations with the &amp;ldquo;customers also bought&amp;rdquo; scroll-list, or Gmail&amp;rsquo;s priority inbox or any email spam-filter feature. How do these work? For Amazon, clicks by the user is used to learn and predict user behavior and propensity (likelihood) to buy certain items. The items the user is most likely to buy are then displayed on the recommendation system. Gmail&amp;rsquo;s system learns from the messages which the user reads and/replies to and prioritizes them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing the future - Data Innovation Labs</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/01/19/designing-the-future-data-innovation-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 16:48:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/01/19/designing-the-future-data-innovation-labs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the ongoing Big data revolution, and the impending Internet of Things revolution, there has been a renewed enthusiasm in &amp;ldquo;innovation&amp;rdquo; around data.  Similar to the Labs concept started by Google (think Gmail Beta based on Ajax, circa 2004), more and more organizations, business communities, governments and countries are setting up Labs to foster innovation in data and analytics technologies. The idea behind these “data innovation labs” is to develop avant-garde data and analytics technologies and products in an agile fashion and move quickly from concept to production. Given the traditional bureaucratic setup in large organizations and governments, these Labs stand a better chance of fostering a culture of innovation, due to their being autonomous entities and their startup-mode culture leveraging agile methodologies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Introduction to Statistics – Part 3 - Statistical Inference</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/01/04/a-brief-introduction-to-statistics-part-3-statistical-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 14:22:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/01/04/a-brief-introduction-to-statistics-part-3-statistical-inference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statistical inference&lt;/strong&gt; is concerned primarily with understanding the quality of parameter estimates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/post/introduction-to-statistical-inference.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Statistical Inference&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sampling distribution represents the distribution of the point estimates based on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;code&gt;samples of a ﬁxed size&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from a certain population. It is useful to think of a particular &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;point estimate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as being drawn from such a distribution. Understanding the concept of a sampling distribution is central to understanding statistical inference.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;sample statistic&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a point estimate for a population parameter, e.g. the sample mean is used to estimate the population mean. &lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: blue;&#34;&gt;Note that point estimate and sample statistic are synonymous.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Recognize that point estimates (such as the sample mean) will vary from one sample to another, and define this variability as sampling variability (sometimes also called sampling variation).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Set up a Hadoop Spark cluster in 10 minutes with Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/30/set-up-a-hadoop-spark-cluster-in-10-minutes-with-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 22:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/30/set-up-a-hadoop-spark-cluster-in-10-minutes-with-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With each of the big 3 Hadoop vendors - &lt;strong&gt;Cloudera&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Hortonworks&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;MapR&lt;/strong&gt; each providing their own Hadoop &lt;span style=&#34;color: blue;&#34;&gt;sandbox&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;virtual machines&lt;/strong&gt; (VMs), trying out Hadoop today has become extremely easy. For a developer, it is extremely useful to download a get started with one of these VMs and try out Hadoop to practice data science right away.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/post/vagrant-hadoop-spark-cluster.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Vagrant Hadoop Spark Cluster&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, with the core &lt;a href=&#34;hadoop.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Apache Hadoop&lt;/a&gt;, these vendors package their own software into their distributions, mostly for the orchestration and management, which can be a pain due to the multiple scattered open-source projects within the Hadoop ecosystem. e.g. Hortonworks includes the open-source &lt;strong&gt;Ambari&lt;/strong&gt; while Cloudera includes its own &lt;strong&gt;Cloudera Manager&lt;/strong&gt; for orchestrating Hadoop installations and managing multi-node clusters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The data science project lifecycle</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/22/the-data-science-project-lifecycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 01:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/22/the-data-science-project-lifecycle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How does the typical data science project life-cycle look like?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post looks at practical aspects of implementing data science projects. It also assumes a certain level of maturity in big data (more on big data maturity models in the next post) and data science management within the organization. Therefore the life cycle presented here differs, sometimes significantly from purist definitions of &amp;lsquo;science&amp;rsquo; which emphasize the hypothesis-testing approach. In practice, the typical data science project life-cycle resembles more of an engineering view imposed due to constraints of resources (budget, data and skills availability) and time-to-market considerations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BI in the digital era</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/19/bi-in-the-digital-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 11:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/19/bi-in-the-digital-era/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometime back I presented a webinar on BrightTalk. The slides for the talk have now been uploaded on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/itsmaloy/bi-in-the-digital-era&#34;&gt;Slideshare&lt;/a&gt;. The talk focused more on changes in digital technology disrupting businesses, the effect of Big Data, the FOMO (Fear of missing out) effect on big business - and what it meant for changes to the way we do business intelligence in the digital era.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;slideshare-embed&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/5lk8abamQrtcTf&#34; &#xA;            width=&#34;595&#34; &#xA;            height=&#34;485&#34; &#xA;            frameborder=&#34;0&#34; &#xA;            marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; &#xA;            marginheight=&#34;0&#34; &#xA;            scrolling=&#34;no&#34; &#xA;            style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; &#xA;            allowfullscreen&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key themes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predictability – Get everything as a service – from IaaS, PaaS and SaaS to XaaS</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/04/predictability-get-everything-as-a-service-from-iaas-paas-and-saas-to-xaas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 18:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/04/predictability-get-everything-as-a-service-from-iaas-paas-and-saas-to-xaas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The outsourcing model which led to the &lt;strong&gt;“on-demand” “as a service”&lt;/strong&gt; model, has taken off with increasing adoption of cloud-computing and mobility. What started out with the SaaS – software as a service model, has now diversified into several other services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, cloud computing has come to rest on three of these as its core pillars:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SaaS: Software as a Service&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;PaaS: Platform as a Service&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;IaaS: Infrastructure as a Service&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Differentiating SaaS, PaaS and IaaS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Introduction to Statistics - Part 2 - Probability and Distributions</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/03/a-brief-introduction-to-statistics-part-2-probability-and-distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 17:22:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/03/a-brief-introduction-to-statistics-part-2-probability-and-distributions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Probability concepts form the foundation for statistics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/post/odds1.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Odds-Probability&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A formal definition of probability&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The probability of an outcome is the proportion of times the outcome would&#xA;occur if we observed the random process an inﬁnite number of times.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is a corollary of the law of large numbers:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As more observations are collected, the proportion of occurrences with a particular outcome converges to the probability of that outcome.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disjoint&lt;/strong&gt; (mutually exclusive) events as events that cannot both happen at the same time. i.e. If &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;B&lt;/code&gt; are disjoint, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;P(A and B) = 0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Complementary&lt;/strong&gt; outcomes as mutually exclusive outcomes of the same random process whose probabilities add up to 1.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;If &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;B&lt;/code&gt; are complementary, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;P(A) + P(B) = 1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now on Amazon - download the BIguru blog  app!</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/11/05/now-on-amazon-download-the-biguru-blog-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 13:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/11/05/now-on-amazon-download-the-biguru-blog-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;BIguru BI Blog app&lt;/strong&gt; is now available on the &lt;strong&gt;Amazon AppStore&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To search and download the app, go to the Amazon AppStore and search for &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com.au/Maloy-Manna-BIguru-BI-Blog/dp/B00NXX5KTW&#34;&gt;Biguru BI Blog&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To download and install, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to follow instructions for your Android smartphone, i.e. you&amp;rsquo;ll need to &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=201482620&#34;&gt;enable unknown sources&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; as outlined by Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/post/8117-umjoml-_sl500_aa300_.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;BIguru BI Blog app&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded and installed it (your smartphone Anti-Virus should scan the app after installation) by accepting the defaults, you&amp;rsquo;re free to get updates on new posts from this blog!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Introduction to Statistics - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/10/28/a-brief-introduction-to-statistics-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 10:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/10/28/a-brief-introduction-to-statistics-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Statistics?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Collected observations are called &lt;strong&gt;data&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Statistics&lt;/strong&gt; is the study of &lt;em&gt;how best to collect, analyze, and draw conclusions from data&lt;/em&gt;. Each observation in data is called a &lt;strong&gt;case&lt;/strong&gt;. Characteristics of the case are called &lt;strong&gt;variables&lt;/strong&gt;. With a matrix/table analogy, a case is a row while a variable is a column.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/post/correlation.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Statistics - Correlation&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Statistics - Correlation (Courtesy: xkcd.com)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Types of variables:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Numerical&lt;/strong&gt; - Can be &lt;strong&gt;discrete&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;continuous&lt;/strong&gt;, and can take a wide range of numerical values.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Data Basics - Part  4 : NoSQL and NewSQL explained</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/10/01/big-data-basics-part-4-nosql-and-newsql-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 08:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/10/01/big-data-basics-part-4-nosql-and-newsql-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maloymanna.github.io/post/nosql.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Big Data Basics: NoSQL and NewSQL&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the fourth part of a series of posts on big data. Read the previous posts here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://biguru.wordpress.com/2013/08/21/basics-of-big-data-part-1/&#34;&gt;Part-1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://biguru.wordpress.com/2014/04/13/basics-of-big-data-part-2-hadoop/&#34;&gt;Part-2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://biguru.wordpress.com/2014/05/12/basics-of-big-data-building-a-hadoop-data-warehouse/&#34;&gt;Part-3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the ongoing data explosion, and the improvement in technologies able to deal with it, businesses are turning to leverage this &lt;span style=&#34;color: blue;&#34;&gt;big data&lt;/span&gt; for mining insights to gain competitive advantage, reinvent business models and create new markets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A huge amount of this &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;big data&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; volumes comes from system logs, user generated content on social media like Twitter or Facebook, sensor data and the like. All of these types of data are what we call &amp;ldquo;unstructured&amp;rdquo;. Businesses which do not leverage the vast amount of unstructured data available to them, risk losing out valuable insights from such data types.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Big Data - Building a Hadoop data warehouse</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/05/12/basics-of-big-data-building-a-hadoop-data-warehouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 12:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/05/12/basics-of-big-data-building-a-hadoop-data-warehouse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the 3rd part of a series of posts on Big Data. Read &lt;a href=&#34;http://biguru.wordpress.com/2013/08/21/basics-of-big-data-part-1/&#34;&gt;Part-1&lt;/a&gt; (What is Big Data) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://biguru.wordpress.com/2014/04/13/basics-of-big-data-part-2-hadoop/&#34;&gt;Part-2 (Hadoop)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Traditionally data warehouses have been built with relational databases as backbone. With the new challenges (&lt;a href=&#34;http://biguru.wordpress.com/2013/08/21/basics-of-big-data-part-1/&#34;&gt;3Vs&lt;/a&gt;) of Big Data, relational databases have been falling short of the requirements of handling&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;New data types (unstructured data)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Extended analytic processing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Throughput (TB/hour loading) with immediate query access&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The industry has turned to Hadoop as a disruptive solution for these very challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Big Data – Part 2 - Hadoop</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/04/13/basics-of-big-data-part-2-hadoop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 18:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/04/13/basics-of-big-data-part-2-hadoop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As discussed in &lt;a href=&#34;http://biguru.wordpress.com/2013/08/21/basics-of-big-data-part-1/&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; of this series, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hadoop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is the foremost among tools being currently used for deriving value out of Big Data. The process of gaining insights from data through Business Intelligence and analytics essentially remains the same. However, with the huge variety, volume and velocity (the 3Vs of Big Data), it’s become necessary to re-think of the data management infrastructure. Hadoop, originally designed to be used with the MapReduce algorithm to solve parallel processing constraints in distributed architectures (e.g. web indexing) of web giants like Yahoo or Google, has become the de-facto standard for Big Data (large-scale data-intensive) analytics platforms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Big Data - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2013/08/21/basics-of-big-data-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 23:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2013/08/21/basics-of-big-data-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can’t miss all the buzz about &lt;strong&gt;Big Data&lt;/strong&gt;! Over the past few years, the buzz around the cloud and &lt;strong&gt;Big Data&lt;/strong&gt; shaping most of the future of computing, IT and analytics in particular has grown incessantly strong. As with most buzz words, which are then hijacked by marketing to suit their own products’ storylines, but which nonetheless manage to confuse users in business and staff in IT as well, &lt;strong&gt;Big Data&lt;/strong&gt; means several things to several people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BI maturity models</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2012/01/08/bi-maturity-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 20:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2012/01/08/bi-maturity-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With most companies listing BI within their top agenda, and with the rising costs and confusion around proving the worth of BI and justifying its costs, it makes sense to try and understand the evolution of BI adoption and maturity in organizations. Knowing what is possible with BI and knowing the challenges and pitfalls allows organizations to plan their BI strategy and implementation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are quite a few schools of thought and available literature on the lifecycle of BI implementation and maturity in organizations, defining the models. Most are proprietary models provided by consultancies, which are primarily based on technical point of view or applies the knowledge management function to BI, following the &lt;strong&gt;Ladder of Business Intelligence (LOBI) model&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in SAP BusinessObjects Enterprise BI 4.0 platform or BOXI 4.0 aka Aurora?</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2011/05/20/whats-new-in-sap-businessobjects-enterprise-bi-4-0-platform-or-boxi-4-0-aka-aurora/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 17:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2011/05/20/whats-new-in-sap-businessobjects-enterprise-bi-4-0-platform-or-boxi-4-0-aka-aurora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SAP BI 4.0 release (codenamed &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aurora&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) has been the first major release of the BI platform since SAP acquired BusinessObjects. In this release, the semantic layer (universe layer for the uninitiated) has been re-worked completely to expose all business data under a single umbrella. The self-service BI portal (aka Infoview) has been revamped with a new AJAX based design and providing quicker and easier access to content. Publishing and distribution of BI content to mass audience has been made easier. There are also improvements to the lifecycle management (LCM tool) and platform administration (CMC, CCM) from a single console. This is in a nutshell are the changes that Aurora or SAP BO 4.0 bring, allowing BI content to be delivered across different channels ranging from the browser (BI Launch Pad, SharePoint, SAP NetWeaver Portal, Java Portal) to desktop (widgets), MS-Office and mobile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analytics - out of the box: SAP Business Analytics</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2010/09/17/analytics-out-of-the-box-sap-business-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2010 13:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2010/09/17/analytics-out-of-the-box-sap-business-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SAP finally &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sap.com/about/newsroom/press.epx?pressid=13894&#34;&gt;announced &lt;/a&gt;on September 14, 2010 that it was getting onto the pre-packaged analytics bandwagon.  SAP announced ten applications in this first release for six industries (Consumer Products, Healthcare, Financial Services, Public Sector, Retail and Telecommunications) in its BusinessObjects  offering.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Building on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sap.com/solutions/sapbusinessobjects/large/eim/rapidmarts/index.epx&#34;&gt;rapid-marts&lt;/a&gt; offering that the then BOBJ used to have and leveraging SAP’s industry and line of business expertise, these new applications are based on the SAP Business Objects XI platform – WebIntelligence, Crystal Reports and Dashboards (formerly Xcelsius). Bill McDermott, the joint CEO of SAP, described it as “&lt;strong&gt;complete and ready-to-go&lt;/strong&gt;” and claimed the applications can be deployed in &lt;em&gt;as less as eight weeks&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of the BT Summit – Cloud computing, SOA and BI tracks</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/11/13/review-of-the-bt-summit--cloud-computing-soa-and-bi-tracks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 08:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/11/13/review-of-the-bt-summit--cloud-computing-soa-and-bi-tracks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I attended the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.btmarch.com/btsummit/&#34;&gt;Business Technology Summit in Bangalore&lt;/a&gt; last week – 3rd and 4th November. There were 3 tracks on cloud computing, Service Oriented Architecture and Business Intelligence, and I chose a mix of sessions across each.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**Overall impression:**The BT Summit was heavily focused on cloud computing with half of second day having a deep dive into Amazon’s EC2 cloud offering, and several keynotes. SOA and web services, REST and similar architectural sessions were interspersed but definitely not a first-class citizen. BI came a poor third with a poor choice of sessions, and more of a rehash of what is out there for everyone, rather than something on the cutting-edge including use of appliances and columnar databases, as also in-memory databases and use of Flash and AJAX for interactive BI front-ends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of the BO XI platform - from XI R2 to XI 3.1 SP2</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/09/15/evolution-of-the-bo-xi-platform-from-xi-r2-to-xi-3-1-sp2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2009 02:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/09/15/evolution-of-the-bo-xi-platform-from-xi-r2-to-xi-3-1-sp2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With BO XI 3.1 SP2 out in July this year, it is probably time to make a trip down the years to find out how the XI platform has evolved and matured.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The timeline:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;XI R2 SP2 - service pack release in March 2007 with productivity pack - QaaWS and LiveOffice connectors&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;XI 3.0 - new major release in February 2008 - the first release after SAP acquired BOBJ in October 2007&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;XI 3.1 - upgrade release in September 2008&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;XI 3.1 SP2 - service pack release on 24 July 2009 - with enhanced SAP integration&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where were we with XI R2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing a Business Objects security model - BO XI 3.1</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/08/28/developing-a-business-objects-security-model-bo-xi-3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 15:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/08/28/developing-a-business-objects-security-model-bo-xi-3-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While developing a Business Objects security model, you need to focus on the different types of security:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Functional Security&lt;/strong&gt; - this would govern access to specific application features, e.g. editing reports, drilling down, ability to schedule reports etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Security&lt;/strong&gt; - this governs access to specific data - rows or columns or cells as per authorization&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure Security&lt;/strong&gt; - governs physical and electronic access to systems&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The infrastructure security is the first to be designed. This typically happens when the architecture is being drawn up. It is important to get as much early visibility into the various ways the system is likely to be used, not only in the present but also in the foreseeable future, so that adjustments and capacity for future planning can be done to the extent possible. This also helps in deciding on the type of data security that would be required initially, though this can change over time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Change the location Google Desktop Search indexes your data</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/07/26/change-the-location-google-desktop-search-indexes-your-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 11:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/07/26/change-the-location-google-desktop-search-indexes-your-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Desktop search has become an important component of our everyday work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the amount of &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.zdnet.com/Gardner/?p=3091&#34;&gt;information explosion&lt;/a&gt;, it is only natural that users and enterprises move towards enabling desktop (and enterprise) search for users – subject of course to appropriate security and access controls. BI vendors have moved into this new business space that has opened up and seems to be one of the most promising. While Business Objects had announced support for the Google Search appliance and Google Desktop &lt;a href=&#34;http://www1.sap.com/about/newsroom/businessobjects/20060515_006446.epx&#34;&gt;back in 2006&lt;/a&gt;, their most important announcement lately has been the launch of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www1.sap.com/solutions/sapbusinessobjects/large/intelligenceplatform/bi/search-navigation/explorer/explorer-non-accelerated/index.epx&#34;&gt;Business Objects Explorer&lt;/a&gt; (formerly known as Polestar) product. More about that in a later post…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BusinessObjects universe design best practices</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/07/19/businessobjects-universe-design-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 22:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/07/19/businessobjects-universe-design-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having relocated from the Silicon Valley to Bangalore a year back, I’m now working in an MIS – strategic reporting role. In my role to evangelize the use of BI best practices and tools, one of the foremost is that of universe design.  As a matter of fact, I’m currently being involved in formalizing a BI policy around the tools we use most – Oracle, Informatica and SAP Business Objects (along with migration from our legacy BO to the XI platform!) – so a lot of my current work is related to best practices, design guidelines and preparing unit test checklists for my team of developers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPC – Using statistics to get insight from BI</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/07/08/spc--using-statistics-to-get-insight-from-bi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2008 13:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/07/08/spc--using-statistics-to-get-insight-from-bi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a well known adage that if you keep doing the same thing and expect different results, that is a sure sign of idiocy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the BI world too, we come across several instances where people take it for granted that the &lt;em&gt;‘BI tool’&lt;/em&gt; will magically generate insight and spur &lt;em&gt;‘intelligence’&lt;/em&gt; rather than &lt;em&gt;‘idiocy’&lt;/em&gt;. Yet the very practices of reporting the same measures, or of creating reports for metrics just because they are now made available by the tool, without sparing any &lt;em&gt;‘intelligence’&lt;/em&gt; into what will generate insight is a major cause  of failures of BI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thrive or Survive - the changing rules for databases</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/05/07/thrive-or-survive-the-changing-rules-for-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 09:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/05/07/thrive-or-survive-the-changing-rules-for-databases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not since the late seventies, when Larry Ellison&amp;rsquo;s Relational Software Inc. (RSI) turned out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/timeline/index.html&#34;&gt;first commerically available RDBMS&lt;/a&gt; - Oracle, has there been such rapid changing of the rules (read disruption) in the database industry.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;With &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web 2.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; pushing enterprise adoption, and the ensuing &lt;em&gt;information explosion&lt;/em&gt; in the maze of audio, video, data and ever-growing data warehouses, it seems that the conventional relational database systems are growing tired. With estimates of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;unstructured data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; being anywhere between 80% to 95% of all business data, and the ever changing requirements imposed by Web 2.0 - storage of &lt;em&gt;pictures&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;audio&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;video&lt;/em&gt;, the demands being made on conventional RDBMS technology are monstrous. With the load window available being fixed due to availability and uptime requirements, the ever increasing data to be loaded into data warehouses, the bulking-up of the data due to usage of &lt;em&gt;XML&lt;/em&gt; based formats, conflicting requirements of &lt;em&gt;SQL&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;XQuery&lt;/em&gt;, the database is also being challenged by the demands of business intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s all in the universe - handling chasm and fan traps</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/05/02/its-all-in-the-universe-handling-chasm-and-fan-traps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2008 05:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/05/02/its-all-in-the-universe-handling-chasm-and-fan-traps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I worked on an assignment where the Business Objects universe was designed by a business analyst. Nothing wrong with that, as long as we get the correct results in reports or queries on the universe. But it was not to be.&#xA;We encountered incorrect results primarily due to two reasons:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mixing of grains in fact tables by not using proper contexts or the aggregate navigator&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unresolved chasm traps&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was obvious that the business analyst was not trained in data modeling, nor did the universe go through a proper QA cycle where it is reviewed for data modeling errors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Export data out of Xcelsius dashboards</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/04/27/export-data-out-of-your-xcelsius-dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 05:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/04/27/export-data-out-of-your-xcelsius-dashboards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Accessing data in Xcelsius is pretty easy. You can have static data loaded from Excel, or dynamic data loaded through Web Services, Excel XML Maps, QaaWS (Query as a Web Service), Crystal Reports, Web Intelligence Reports or queries using Live Office.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are however only a few ways to export data from Xcelsius. Either we could use Flash variables or use the XML Data Button to export data out of the compiled .swf file.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Development for BI</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/04/07/agile-development-for-bi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 05:43:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/04/07/agile-development-for-bi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How can you reduce development costs and improve software reliability and accuracy at the same time? How can you make IT work together with Business while architect-ing your BI applications? If these goals sound contradictory and difficult to achieve, then Agile development may well fit the bill. Indeed in numerous BI projects, one or the other flavor of Agile is used to attain these very goals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Defining Agile&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;There are several Agile development methodologies available:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP drops Business Objects Performance Management</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/03/29/sap-drops-business-objects-performance-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2008 04:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/03/29/sap-drops-business-objects-performance-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In what seems to be a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoworld.com/article/08/03/28/SAP-retires-overlapping-BI-products_1.html&#34;&gt;speedy decision&lt;/a&gt; to clean up an overlapping product line, following its acquisition of Business Objects (&lt;a href=&#34;http://finance.google.com/finance?q=NASDAQ%3ABOBJ&#34;&gt;BOBJ&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&#34;http://sap.com&#34;&gt;SAP&lt;/a&gt; has decided to retire the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessobjects.com/product/epm/&#34;&gt;Business Objects Performance Management&lt;/a&gt; product.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Taking its place would be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sap.com/demos/demplayv2/demoPlayMaster.html?demos/Strategy_Management_US/Strategy_Management_US_config.xml&#34;&gt;SAP Strategy Management&lt;/a&gt; (a product &lt;a href=&#34;http://biguru.wordpress.com/about/&#34;&gt;biguru&lt;/a&gt; is SAP certified). &lt;strong&gt;SAP Strategy Management&lt;/strong&gt; is the new name for what used to be Pilot Software&amp;rsquo;s flagship product &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sap.com/usa/company/press/pilotsoftware/index.epx&#34;&gt;PilotWorks&lt;/a&gt; product, which SAP acquired in February 2007. No doubt about the fact that PilotWorks Server which is based on a powerful OLAP engine, and has an extremely user-friendly GUI on top of it, is a few notches above the clunky Performance Manager of &lt;a href=&#34;http://finance.google.com/finance?q=NASDAQ%3ABOBJ&#34;&gt;BOBJ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in Xcelsius 2008 - Top 10 features</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/03/20/whats-new-in-xcelsius-2008-top-10-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2008 05:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/03/20/whats-new-in-xcelsius-2008-top-10-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Business Objects has just released the updated &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessobjects.com/product/catalog/xcelsius/default.asp&#34;&gt;Xcelsius 2008&lt;/a&gt; after a long &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessobjects.com/campaigns/xcelsius/contest/&#34;&gt;beta program&lt;/a&gt;. What are the top new features of this exciting data visualization and dashboard tool? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out the top 10:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copy-Paste&lt;/strong&gt;- Productivity is bound to increase through collaborative development now as it is possible to copy-paste components between XLF files.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filtered Rows&lt;/strong&gt; - Selector components like List box and combo-box now include a new option in the insert-options list. This is the &amp;ldquo;Filtered rows&amp;rdquo; option, automatically removing duplicates. In the previous version, this worked only with the Filter component.t&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SaaS BI - Software as a service model in Business Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/03/14/saas-bi-software-as-a-service-model-in-business-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 04:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/03/14/saas-bi-software-as-a-service-model-in-business-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SaaS has taken off in a big way in the past few years. And BI has not been lagging behind. For leading vendors like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessobjects.com/&#34;&gt;BOBJ&lt;/a&gt; (an SAP company) or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cognos.com/&#34;&gt;Cognos&lt;/a&gt; (an IBM company), it&amp;rsquo;s going to be close to 2 years now since they started their SaaS BI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What exactly are the advantages of SaaS over the traditional approach?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Benefits are aplenty, from zero costs of purchasing hardware, hiring of key IT personnel like system administrators and DBAs, to minimal implementation and maintenance costs. With CRM being made affordable to SME (small and medium-sized enterprises) by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.salesforce.com&#34;&gt;salesforce.com&lt;/a&gt; (note the huge success of its &lt;strong&gt;AppExchange&lt;/strong&gt;), and the fact that large enterprise adoption of BI was complete, meant that the only scope for future growth in BI would come from upgrades of platforms (analogous to Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Windows operating system - think of BOBJ upgrading from 6.5 to XI) or from expansion in the SME space with better offerings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acquisitions in BI - End of the best of breed?</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/12/20/acquisitions-in-bi-end-of-the-best-of-breed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 05:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/12/20/acquisitions-in-bi-end-of-the-best-of-breed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last time I talked about the trends in the BI space. Let&amp;rsquo;s look into one of those trends - M&amp;amp;As and how it is shaping BI as we know it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A recent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessweek.com/technology/content/nov2007/tc20071112_678294.htm&#34;&gt;BusinessWeek article&lt;/a&gt; claimed the end of the &lt;strong&gt;best-of-breed&lt;/strong&gt; approach to BI with the demise of the major pure-play BI vendors like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessobjects.com&#34;&gt;BOBJ&lt;/a&gt; now owned by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sap.com&#34;&gt;SAP&lt;/a&gt; thanks to a friendly takeover or Hyperion acquired by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com&#34;&gt;Oracle &lt;/a&gt;or the latest - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ibm.com&#34;&gt;IBM&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s acquisition of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cognos.com&#34;&gt;Cognos&lt;/a&gt;. While it is true that some of the major players have been acquired by the bigger businesses, there is no reason as to why the mid-size companies should go out of business.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trends in Business Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/12/10/trends-in-business-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2007 20:33:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/12/10/trends-in-business-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By definition Business Intelligence (&lt;strong&gt;BI&lt;/strong&gt;) has been about making decisions based on information obtained from meaningful data. At one point of time we had terms like decision support systems (&lt;strong&gt;DSS&lt;/strong&gt;) to define technology which has finally evolved into BI as we know it now. Or has it? Somewhere along the line, we became entangled in the technology aspect of it and with all the buzzwords of data warehousing, data mining, dimensional modeling, data marts, **CRM **and **SCM **it is not difficult to see why. It is only of late that the focus has moved back to the &amp;ldquo;decision making&amp;rdquo; aspect of BI rather than focusing on the technology &lt;em&gt;per se&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/11/30/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/11/30/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog is going to have a series of posts about trends and recent happenings in the BI space, some theory on data warehousing and BI - classical as well as newer approaches. It will also feature some tutorials on some technologies and implementations I have worked with as well as useful links.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;~biguru&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
