<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BI on Maloy Manna</title>
    <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/tags/bi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BI on Maloy Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2007 - 2025. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 17:54:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://maloymanna.github.io/tags/bi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in SAP BusinessObjects Enterprise BI 4.0 platform or BOXI 4.0 aka Aurora?</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2011/05/20/whats-new-in-sap-businessobjects-enterprise-bi-4-0-platform-or-boxi-4-0-aka-aurora/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 17:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2011/05/20/whats-new-in-sap-businessobjects-enterprise-bi-4-0-platform-or-boxi-4-0-aka-aurora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SAP BI 4.0 release (codenamed &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aurora&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) has been the first major release of the BI platform since SAP acquired BusinessObjects. In this release, the semantic layer (universe layer for the uninitiated) has been re-worked completely to expose all business data under a single umbrella. The self-service BI portal (aka Infoview) has been revamped with a new AJAX based design and providing quicker and easier access to content. Publishing and distribution of BI content to mass audience has been made easier. There are also improvements to the lifecycle management (LCM tool) and platform administration (CMC, CCM) from a single console. This is in a nutshell are the changes that Aurora or SAP BO 4.0 bring, allowing BI content to be delivered across different channels ranging from the browser (BI Launch Pad, SharePoint, SAP NetWeaver Portal, Java Portal) to desktop (widgets), MS-Office and mobile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/11/30/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/11/30/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog is going to have a series of posts about trends and recent happenings in the BI space, some theory on data warehousing and BI - classical as well as newer approaches. It will also feature some tutorials on some technologies and implementations I have worked with as well as useful links.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;~biguru&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
