<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Maloy Manna</title>
    <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Maloy Manna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2007 - 2020. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 11:37:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://maloymanna.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data processing with Spark in R &amp; Python</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/11/18/data-processing-with-spark-in-r-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 11:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/11/18/data-processing-with-spark-in-r-python/</guid>
      <description>I recently gave a talk on data processing with Apache Spark using R and Python. tl;dr - the slides and presentation can be accessed below (free registration):
   As noted in my previous post, Spark has become the defacto standard for big data applications and has been adopted quickly by the industry. See Cloudera&amp;rsquo;s One Platform initiative blog post by CEO Mike Olson for their commitment to Spark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What roles do you need in your data science team?</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/06/24/what-roles-do-you-need-in-your-data-science-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 22:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/06/24/what-roles-do-you-need-in-your-data-science-team/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few weeks, we&amp;rsquo;ve had several conversations in our data lab regarding data engineering problems and day to day problems we face with unsupervised data scientists who find it difficult to deploy their code into production.
The opinions from business seemed to cluster around a tacit definition of data scientists as researchers, primarily from statistics or mathematics backgrounds, who are experienced in machine learning algorithms and often in some domain areas specific to our business, (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to Data Science</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/05/20/an-introduction-to-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 16:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/05/20/an-introduction-to-data-science/</guid>
      <description>I presented a talk last week introducing Data Science and associated topics to some enthusiasts.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a slide deck I created quickly with markdown using Swipe - a start-up building HTML5 presentation tools.
The contents include:
 Data scientist skills Data science: enablers and barriers Big data analytics Data science lifecycle Use cases Tools and technology Project approach Machine learning Skills and roles Learning resources  Here are the slides:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Spark is the big data platform of the future</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/03/23/spark-big-data-platform-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 12:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/03/23/spark-big-data-platform-future/</guid>
      <description>Apache Spark has created a lot of buzz recently. In fact, beyond the buzz, Apache Spark has seen phenomenal adoption and has been marked out as the successor to Hadoop MapReduce.
Google Trends confirms the hockey stick like growth in interest in Apache Spark. All leading Hadoop vendors, including Cloudera, now include Apache Spark in their Hadoop distribution.
So what exactly is Spark, and why has it generated such enthusiasm? Apache Spark is an open-source big data processing framework designed for speed and ease of use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A gentle introduction to Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/02/04/a-gentle-introduction-to-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 23:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/02/04/a-gentle-introduction-to-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning is a big part of big data and data science. A subset of artificial intelligence - a branch of science notorious for requiring advanced knowledge of mathematics. In practice though, most data scientists don&amp;rsquo;t try to build a Chappie and there are simpler, practical ways to get started with machine learning.
Machine learning in practice involves predictions based on data. Notable examples include Amazon&amp;rsquo;s product recommendations with the &amp;ldquo;customers also bought&amp;rdquo; scroll-list, or Gmail&amp;rsquo;s priority inbox or any email spam-filter feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing the future - Data Innovation Labs</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/01/19/designing-the-future-data-innovation-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 16:48:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/01/19/designing-the-future-data-innovation-labs/</guid>
      <description>With the ongoing Big data revolution, and the impending Internet of Things revolution, there has been a renewed enthusiasm in &amp;ldquo;innovation&amp;rdquo; around data. Similar to the Labs concept started by Google (think Gmail Beta based on Ajax, circa 2004), more and more organizations, business communities, governments and countries are setting up Labs to foster innovation in data and analytics technologies. The idea behind these “data innovation labs” is to develop avant-garde data and analytics technologies and products in an agile fashion and move quickly from concept to production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Introduction to Statistics – Part 3 - Statistical Inference</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/01/04/a-brief-introduction-to-statistics-part-3-statistical-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 14:22:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2015/01/04/a-brief-introduction-to-statistics-part-3-statistical-inference/</guid>
      <description>Statistical inference is concerned primarily with understanding the quality of parameter estimates.
The sampling distribution represents the distribution of the point estimates based on samples of a ﬁxed size from a certain population. It is useful to think of a particular point estimate as being drawn from such a distribution. Understanding the concept of a sampling distribution is central to understanding statistical inference.
A sample statistic is a point estimate for a population parameter, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up a Hadoop Spark cluster in 10 minutes with Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/30/set-up-a-hadoop-spark-cluster-in-10-minutes-with-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 22:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/30/set-up-a-hadoop-spark-cluster-in-10-minutes-with-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>With each of the big 3 Hadoop vendors - Cloudera, Hortonworks and MapR each providing their own Hadoop sandbox virtual machines (VMs), trying out Hadoop today has become extremely easy. For a developer, it is extremely useful to download a get started with one of these VMs and try out Hadoop to practice data science right away.
However, with the core Apache Hadoop, these vendors package their own software into their distributions, mostly for the orchestration and management, which can be a pain due to the multiple scattered open-source projects within the Hadoop ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The data science project lifecycle</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/22/the-data-science-project-lifecycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 01:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/22/the-data-science-project-lifecycle/</guid>
      <description>How does the typical data science project life-cycle look like?
This post looks at practical aspects of implementing data science projects. It also assumes a certain level of maturity in big data (more on big data maturity models in the next post) and data science management within the organization. Therefore the life cycle presented here differs, sometimes significantly from purist definitions of &amp;lsquo;science&amp;rsquo; which emphasize the hypothesis-testing approach. In practice, the typical data science project life-cycle resembles more of an engineering view imposed due to constraints of resources (budget, data and skills availability) and time-to-market considerations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BI in the digital era</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/19/bi-in-the-digital-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 11:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/19/bi-in-the-digital-era/</guid>
      <description>Sometime back I presented a webinar on BrightTalk. The slides for the talk have now been uploaded on Slideshare. The talk focused more on changes in digital technology disrupting businesses, the effect of Big Data, the FOMO (Fear of missing out) effect on big business - and what it meant for changes to the way we do business intelligence in the digital era.
 Key themes:
 Disruption in traditional IT with cloud computing Changing economics and changing business models Rise of Big Data Tech changes to manage Big Data - distributed computing Shift from &amp;ldquo;current-state&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;next-state&amp;rdquo; questions Introducing Data Science Challenges - regulatory, data privacy Dangers of data science - over-fitting, interpretation Managing big data projects Data Science MOOCs (massive open online courses), tools and resources</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictability – Get everything as a service – from IaaS, PaaS and SaaS to XaaS</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/04/predictability-get-everything-as-a-service-from-iaas-paas-and-saas-to-xaas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 18:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/04/predictability-get-everything-as-a-service-from-iaas-paas-and-saas-to-xaas/</guid>
      <description>The outsourcing model which led to the “on-demand” “as a service” model, has taken off with increasing adoption of cloud-computing and mobility. What started out with the SaaS – software as a service model, has now diversified into several other services.
Indeed, cloud computing has come to rest on three of these as its core pillars:
 SaaS: Software as a Service PaaS: Platform as a Service IaaS: Infrastructure as a Service  Differentiating SaaS, PaaS and IaaS:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Introduction to Statistics - Part 2 - Probability and Distributions</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/03/a-brief-introduction-to-statistics-part-2-probability-and-distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 17:22:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/12/03/a-brief-introduction-to-statistics-part-2-probability-and-distributions/</guid>
      <description>Probability concepts form the foundation for statistics.
A formal definition of probability:
The probability of an outcome is the proportion of times the outcome would occur if we observed the random process an inﬁnite number of times.
This is a corollary of the law of large numbers:
As more observations are collected, the proportion of occurrences with a particular outcome converges to the probability of that outcome.
Disjoint (mutually exclusive) events as events that cannot both happen at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now on Amazon - download the BIguru blog  app!</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/11/05/now-on-amazon-download-the-biguru-blog-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 13:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/11/05/now-on-amazon-download-the-biguru-blog-app/</guid>
      <description>The BIguru BI Blog app is now available on the Amazon AppStore!
To search and download the app, go to the Amazon AppStore and search for &amp;ldquo;Biguru BI Blog&amp;rdquo;.
To download and install, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to follow instructions for your Android smartphone, i.e. you&amp;rsquo;ll need to &amp;ldquo;enable unknown sources&amp;rdquo; as outlined by Amazon.
Once you&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded and installed it (your smartphone Anti-Virus should scan the app after installation) by accepting the defaults, you&amp;rsquo;re free to get updates on new posts from this blog!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Introduction to Statistics - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/10/28/a-brief-introduction-to-statistics-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 10:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/10/28/a-brief-introduction-to-statistics-part-1/</guid>
      <description>What is Statistics?
Collected observations are called data. Statistics is the study of how best to collect, analyze, and draw conclusions from data. Each observation in data is called a case. Characteristics of the case are called variables. With a matrix/table analogy, a case is a row while a variable is a column.
Statistics - Correlation (Courtesy: xkcd.com)
Types of variables:
 Numerical - Can be discrete or continuous, and can take a wide range of numerical values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data Basics - Part  4 : NoSQL and NewSQL explained</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/10/01/big-data-basics-part-4-nosql-and-newsql-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 08:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/10/01/big-data-basics-part-4-nosql-and-newsql-explained/</guid>
      <description>This is the fourth part of a series of posts on big data. Read the previous posts here: Part-1, Part-2 and Part-3.
With the ongoing data explosion, and the improvement in technologies able to deal with it, businesses are turning to leverage this big data for mining insights to gain competitive advantage, reinvent business models and create new markets.
A huge amount of this &amp;ldquo;big data&amp;rdquo; volumes comes from system logs, user generated content on social media like Twitter or Facebook, sensor data and the like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Big Data - Building a Hadoop data warehouse</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/05/12/basics-of-big-data-building-a-hadoop-data-warehouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 12:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/05/12/basics-of-big-data-building-a-hadoop-data-warehouse/</guid>
      <description>This is the 3rd part of a series of posts on Big Data. Read Part-1 (What is Big Data) and Part-2 (Hadoop).
Traditionally data warehouses have been built with relational databases as backbone. With the new challenges (3Vs) of Big Data, relational databases have been falling short of the requirements of handling
 New data types (unstructured data) Extended analytic processing Throughput (TB/hour loading) with immediate query access  The industry has turned to Hadoop as a disruptive solution for these very challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Big Data – Part 2 - Hadoop</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/04/13/basics-of-big-data-part-2-hadoop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 18:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2014/04/13/basics-of-big-data-part-2-hadoop/</guid>
      <description>As discussed in Part 1 of this series, Hadoop is the foremost among tools being currently used for deriving value out of Big Data. The process of gaining insights from data through Business Intelligence and analytics essentially remains the same. However, with the huge variety, volume and velocity (the 3Vs of Big Data), it’s become necessary to re-think of the data management infrastructure. Hadoop, originally designed to be used with the MapReduce algorithm to solve parallel processing constraints in distributed architectures (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Big Data - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2013/08/21/basics-of-big-data-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 23:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2013/08/21/basics-of-big-data-part-1/</guid>
      <description>You can’t miss all the buzz about Big Data! Over the past few years, the buzz around the cloud and Big Data shaping most of the future of computing, IT and analytics in particular has grown incessantly strong. As with most buzz words, which are then hijacked by marketing to suit their own products’ storylines, but which nonetheless manage to confuse users in business and staff in IT as well, Big Data means several things to several people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BI maturity models</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2012/01/08/bi-maturity-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 20:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2012/01/08/bi-maturity-models/</guid>
      <description>With most companies listing BI within their top agenda, and with the rising costs and confusion around proving the worth of BI and justifying its costs, it makes sense to try and understand the evolution of BI adoption and maturity in organizations. Knowing what is possible with BI and knowing the challenges and pitfalls allows organizations to plan their BI strategy and implementation.
There are quite a few schools of thought and available literature on the lifecycle of BI implementation and maturity in organizations, defining the models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in SAP BusinessObjects Enterprise BI 4.0 platform or BOXI 4.0 aka Aurora?</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2011/05/20/whats-new-in-sap-businessobjects-enterprise-bi-4-0-platform-or-boxi-4-0-aka-aurora/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 17:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2011/05/20/whats-new-in-sap-businessobjects-enterprise-bi-4-0-platform-or-boxi-4-0-aka-aurora/</guid>
      <description>SAP BI 4.0 release (codenamed Aurora) has been the first major release of the BI platform since SAP acquired BusinessObjects. In this release, the semantic layer (universe layer for the uninitiated) has been re-worked completely to expose all business data under a single umbrella. The self-service BI portal (aka Infoview) has been revamped with a new AJAX based design and providing quicker and easier access to content. Publishing and distribution of BI content to mass audience has been made easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics - out of the box: SAP Business Analytics</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2010/09/17/analytics-out-of-the-box-sap-business-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2010 13:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2010/09/17/analytics-out-of-the-box-sap-business-analytics/</guid>
      <description>SAP finally announced on September 14, 2010 that it was getting onto the pre-packaged analytics bandwagon. SAP announced ten applications in this first release for six industries (Consumer Products, Healthcare, Financial Services, Public Sector, Retail and Telecommunications) in its BusinessObjects offering.
Building on the rapid-marts offering that the then BOBJ used to have and leveraging SAP’s industry and line of business expertise, these new applications are based on the SAP Business Objects XI platform – WebIntelligence, Crystal Reports and Dashboards (formerly Xcelsius).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of the BT Summit – Cloud computing, SOA and BI tracks</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/11/13/review-of-the-bt-summit-cloud-computing-soa-and-bi-tracks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 08:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/11/13/review-of-the-bt-summit-cloud-computing-soa-and-bi-tracks/</guid>
      <description>I attended the Business Technology Summit in Bangalore last week – 3rd and 4th November. There were 3 tracks on cloud computing, Service Oriented Architecture and Business Intelligence, and I chose a mix of sessions across each.
Overall impression:The BT Summit was heavily focused on cloud computing with half of second day having a deep dive into Amazon’s EC2 cloud offering, and several keynotes. SOA and web services, REST and similar architectural sessions were interspersed but definitely not a first-class citizen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of the BO XI platform - from XI R2 to XI 3.1 SP2</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/09/15/evolution-of-the-bo-xi-platform-from-xi-r2-to-xi-3-1-sp2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2009 02:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/09/15/evolution-of-the-bo-xi-platform-from-xi-r2-to-xi-3-1-sp2/</guid>
      <description>With BO XI 3.1 SP2 out in July this year, it is probably time to make a trip down the years to find out how the XI platform has evolved and matured.
The timeline:
 XI R2 SP2 - service pack release in March 2007 with productivity pack - QaaWS and LiveOffice connectors XI 3.0 - new major release in February 2008 - the first release after SAP acquired BOBJ in October 2007 XI 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing a Business Objects security model - BO XI 3.1</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/08/28/developing-a-business-objects-security-model-bo-xi-3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 15:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/08/28/developing-a-business-objects-security-model-bo-xi-3-1/</guid>
      <description>While developing a Business Objects security model, you need to focus on the different types of security:
 Functional Security - this would govern access to specific application features, e.g. editing reports, drilling down, ability to schedule reports etc.
 Data Security - this governs access to specific data - rows or columns or cells as per authorization
 Infrastructure Security - governs physical and electronic access to systems
  The infrastructure security is the first to be designed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change the location Google Desktop Search indexes your data</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/07/26/change-the-location-google-desktop-search-indexes-your-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 11:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/07/26/change-the-location-google-desktop-search-indexes-your-data/</guid>
      <description>Desktop search has become an important component of our everyday work.
With the amount of information explosion, it is only natural that users and enterprises move towards enabling desktop (and enterprise) search for users – subject of course to appropriate security and access controls. BI vendors have moved into this new business space that has opened up and seems to be one of the most promising. While Business Objects had announced support for the Google Search appliance and Google Desktop back in 2006, their most important announcement lately has been the launch of the Business Objects Explorer (formerly known as Polestar) product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BusinessObjects universe design best practices</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/07/19/businessobjects-universe-design-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 22:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2009/07/19/businessobjects-universe-design-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>Having relocated from the Silicon Valley to Bangalore a year back, I’m now working in an MIS – strategic reporting role. In my role to evangelize the use of BI best practices and tools, one of the foremost is that of universe design. As a matter of fact, I’m currently being involved in formalizing a BI policy around the tools we use most – Oracle, Informatica and SAP Business Objects (along with migration from our legacy BO to the XI platform!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPC – Using statistics to get insight from BI</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/07/08/spc-using-statistics-to-get-insight-from-bi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2008 13:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/07/08/spc-using-statistics-to-get-insight-from-bi/</guid>
      <description>There is a well known adage that if you keep doing the same thing and expect different results, that is a sure sign of idiocy.
In the BI world too, we come across several instances where people take it for granted that the ‘BI tool’ will magically generate insight and spur ‘intelligence’ rather than ‘idiocy’. Yet the very practices of reporting the same measures, or of creating reports for metrics just because they are now made available by the tool, without sparing any ‘intelligence’ into what will generate insight is a major cause of failures of BI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thrive or Survive - the changing rules for databases</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/05/07/thrive-or-survive-the-changing-rules-for-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 09:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/05/07/thrive-or-survive-the-changing-rules-for-databases/</guid>
      <description>Not since the late seventies, when Larry Ellison&amp;rsquo;s Relational Software Inc. (RSI) turned out the first commerically available RDBMS - Oracle, has there been such rapid changing of the rules (read disruption) in the database industry.
With Web 2.0 pushing enterprise adoption, and the ensuing information explosion in the maze of audio, video, data and ever-growing data warehouses, it seems that the conventional relational database systems are growing tired. With estimates of unstructured data being anywhere between 80% to 95% of all business data, and the ever changing requirements imposed by Web 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s all in the universe - handling chasm and fan traps</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/05/02/its-all-in-the-universe-handling-chasm-and-fan-traps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2008 05:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/05/02/its-all-in-the-universe-handling-chasm-and-fan-traps/</guid>
      <description>Recently I worked on an assignment where the Business Objects universe was designed by a business analyst. Nothing wrong with that, as long as we get the correct results in reports or queries on the universe. But it was not to be. We encountered incorrect results primarily due to two reasons:
 Mixing of grains in fact tables by not using proper contexts or the aggregate navigator
 Unresolved chasm traps</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Export data out of Xcelsius dashboards</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/04/27/export-data-out-of-your-xcelsius-dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 05:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/04/27/export-data-out-of-your-xcelsius-dashboards/</guid>
      <description>Accessing data in Xcelsius is pretty easy. You can have static data loaded from Excel, or dynamic data loaded through Web Services, Excel XML Maps, QaaWS (Query as a Web Service), Crystal Reports, Web Intelligence Reports or queries using Live Office.
There are however only a few ways to export data from Xcelsius. Either we could use Flash variables or use the XML Data Button to export data out of the compiled .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile Development for BI</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/04/07/agile-development-for-bi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 05:43:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/04/07/agile-development-for-bi/</guid>
      <description>How can you reduce development costs and improve software reliability and accuracy at the same time? How can you make IT work together with Business while architect-ing your BI applications? If these goals sound contradictory and difficult to achieve, then Agile development may well fit the bill. Indeed in numerous BI projects, one or the other flavor of Agile is used to attain these very goals.
Defining Agile There are several Agile development methodologies available:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAP drops Business Objects Performance Management</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/03/29/sap-drops-business-objects-performance-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2008 04:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/03/29/sap-drops-business-objects-performance-management/</guid>
      <description>In what seems to be a speedy decision to clean up an overlapping product line, following its acquisition of Business Objects (BOBJ), SAP has decided to retire the Business Objects Performance Management product.
Taking its place would be SAP Strategy Management (a product biguru is SAP certified). SAP Strategy Management is the new name for what used to be Pilot Software&amp;rsquo;s flagship product PilotWorks product, which SAP acquired in February 2007.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in Xcelsius 2008 - Top 10 features</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/03/20/whats-new-in-xcelsius-2008-top-10-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2008 05:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/03/20/whats-new-in-xcelsius-2008-top-10-features/</guid>
      <description>Business Objects has just released the updated Xcelsius 2008 after a long beta program. What are the top new features of this exciting data visualization and dashboard tool? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out the top 10:
 Copy-Paste- Productivity is bound to increase through collaborative development now as it is possible to copy-paste components between XLF files.
 Filtered Rows - Selector components like List box and combo-box now include a new option in the insert-options list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SaaS BI - Software as a service model in Business Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/03/14/saas-bi-software-as-a-service-model-in-business-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 04:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2008/03/14/saas-bi-software-as-a-service-model-in-business-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>SaaS has taken off in a big way in the past few years. And BI has not been lagging behind. For leading vendors like BOBJ (an SAP company) or Cognos (an IBM company), it&amp;rsquo;s going to be close to 2 years now since they started their SaaS BI.
What exactly are the advantages of SaaS over the traditional approach?
Benefits are aplenty, from zero costs of purchasing hardware, hiring of key IT personnel like system administrators and DBAs, to minimal implementation and maintenance costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acquisitions in BI - End of the best of breed?</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/12/20/acquisitions-in-bi-end-of-the-best-of-breed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 05:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/12/20/acquisitions-in-bi-end-of-the-best-of-breed/</guid>
      <description>Last time I talked about the trends in the BI space. Let&amp;rsquo;s look into one of those trends - M&amp;amp;As and how it is shaping BI as we know it.
A recent BusinessWeek article claimed the end of the best-of-breed approach to BI with the demise of the major pure-play BI vendors like BOBJ now owned by SAP thanks to a friendly takeover or Hyperion acquired by Oracle or the latest - IBM&amp;rsquo;s acquisition of Cognos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trends in Business Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/12/10/trends-in-business-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2007 20:33:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/12/10/trends-in-business-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>By definition Business Intelligence (BI) has been about making decisions based on information obtained from meaningful data. At one point of time we had terms like decision support systems (DSS) to define technology which has finally evolved into BI as we know it now. Or has it? Somewhere along the line, we became entangled in the technology aspect of it and with all the buzzwords of data warehousing, data mining, dimensional modeling, data marts, **CRM **and **SCM **it is not difficult to see why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/11/30/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maloymanna.github.io/2007/11/30/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>This blog is going to have a series of posts about trends and recent happenings in the BI space, some theory on data warehousing and BI - classical as well as newer approaches. It will also feature some tutorials on some technologies and implementations I have worked with as well as useful links.
~biguru</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>